# **YE YUAN**

Email: andyyuan2017@gmail.com | Phone: 0426500519 | Sydney, NSW

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/ye-andy-yuan

#### **Career Profile**

Completed a 2-year Master of Engineering Science (Mechanical engineering) and a 4-year Bachelor of Engineering (Mechanical engineering)

Gain advanced Solidworks, and ANSYS skills through projects in UNSW and DLUT.

Multitask ability and ability to work under high stress through 6-month kitchen hand experience.

Completed 1 bidding document and 3 Feasibility Study Reports (FSR) for government construction projects. Self-study programmer in Python and web development.

#### **Education**

# **Master of Engineering Science (Mechanical Engineering)**

Feb 2017-Nov 2018

University of New South Wales (UNSW), Sydney

 $Bachelor\ of\ Engineering\ (Mechanical\ design\ and\ manufacturing\ Engineering\ )$ 

Sep.2012-Jun 2016

Dalian University of Technology (DUT), China

# **Relevant Experience**

#### **Assistant Cost Consultant**

Aug 2016-Jan 2017

#### Zhongshi Engineering Bidding Consultation Co.

Nei Mongol, China

- -Completed 1 bidding document on Energy Consumption and Profitability Estimation for Mining Site Construction and 5-year Operation using Microsoft Excel and Word.
- -Prepared 3 Feasibility Study Reports (FSR) for construction companies on local government projects using Microsoft Excel and Word:

Constructing main roads and highway green belt

Constructing large scale farm for Aberdeen Angus

Replacing old urban road lighting, draining system, and green belt

-Coordinate with government project managers according to report needs

# **Mechanical Engineering internship**

Mar 2015-Jun 2015

# **AVIC Shenyang Aero-Engine group corporation**

Liaoning, China

- -Comprehended the military scale Aero Engine production procedure.
- -Comprehended the main manufacturing process craft requirements.
- -Familiar with the factory safety requirement.

#### **Additional Experience**

Kitchen hand

Nov 2018-May 2019

Maroubra Seals Club

Sydney, NSW

In responsible for salad making, dishes decoration, and ingredient preparation in an extremely fast-paced kitchen.

# Waiter and duty manager

Maroubra Seals Club

Nov 2018-May 2019 Sydney, NSW

Providing good quality table service, waiter management, and training new staff.

#### **Projects**

# Redesigning golf cart prototype for mass production purposes.

Jun 2018-Nov 2018

Redesigned the prototype of a golf cart as a group. In responsible for modeling and redesign of all structural parts for manufacturing purpose and lighter weight in the aid of ANSYS and Solidworks followed VDI2221.

# Porous media camp stove design

Sep 2017-Nov 2017

Designed a prototype camp stove from the sketch as a group.

3D modeling of the prototype using Solidworks, and adjusted the structure according to the property of porous media.

Designed a fan structure for better heat absorption according to ANSYS results.

Generated 2D CAD drawings (parts and assembly) in Australian Standard for further production.

Course score: 85% (HD)

# Designed and tested the micro grove structure in the micro heat pipe.

Mar 2016-Jun 2016

Designed and fabricated the micro heat pipe behind a LED matrix, and tested the performance.

Thesis: Wick Structure Optimization for Micro Heat Pipe

Course score: 81% (D)

# Specialized milling fixture designing and drafting

Sep 2015- Dec 2015

Design and freehand drafted a specialized fixture for milling of a connector according to the 2D draft of the connector in Chinese Standard

#### Skills

-Solidworks	-Leadership and communication skills
-ANSYS	-Multitask ability
-Autodesk Inventor	-Python
-AutoCAD	-Html
-Microsoft office WORD, PPT	-CSS3
-MATLAB	-JavaScript
-Engineer Australia Certification (Mechanical	-PTE 70
Engineering)	-NAATI Translator certificate